# HARI KRISHNA G

Hyderabad, Telangana, India  $_{\bullet}$  +91 9000099226  $_{\bullet}$  harirordeveloper@gmail.com

A hariror.dev



# Sr Software Engineer

# Summary

A full-stack Ruby on Rails Developer Having 9 years experience in developing Ruby, Ruby on Rails applications. Well versed with HTML, HAML, CSS & Javascript, PostgresSQL, MYSQL, MONGODB, JQuery, Ajax, JQuery Mobile, Zrub Foundation, Twitter Bootstrap, BackBone JS, Angular and React JS.

Experience in API integration with systems such as Facebook, Twitter, Linkedin, etc., as well as writing API's to allow external systems to connect to us. Have built a complete stripe based payment platform(Paythen). Building performance oriented systems by use of caching, rails best practices, TDD with R Spec and Jasmine for JavaScript coverage. Having strong knowledge on Object Oriented Programming. Have been working on Linux (UBUNTU) for past 9 years.

Having experience with creating and deploying applications to AWS and Heroku as DevOps.

### **Experience Summary:**

Presently working as "Sr. Software Engineer" in Orange Bicycle Company since January 2017 as remote developer from India. Worked as Sr. Software Engineer in Value Labs, from March 2014 to June 2015. Worked as Sr. Software Engineer in NOTOUS INNOVATIONS INC Pvt Ltd, from March 2013 to March 2014.

	Sk	ills —	
Ruby		Ruby on Rails	
AWS		Heroku	
Deployment to aws servers		Deploying apps to Heroku pipelines	
JavaScript		ReactJS	
Query		Angular JS	
	Work ex	perience ———————————————————————————————————	
	ware Engineer eBicycle Co		

My responsibilities :

Leadership Index (leadershipindex.com.au).

• To understand the requirements and give the technical estimates.

Currently i'm working on 3 projects of this organisation Paythen( paythen.co ), Timblee (timblee.io),

- Developing the requirements that are estimated.
- Development for business logic with Ruby on rails.
- Deploying applications to AWS and Heroku as part of my DevOps roll.
- Reviewing the code submitted by other developers.
- Guiding the junior developers for better results.

#### JUIY 2015 - JAN 2017

# Senior Software Engineer

Sumeru Solutions

Worked as Senior Software Engineer in Sumeru Solutions. Worked on a project called Ygrene. I have worked for a project called MDLIVE. My responsibility is to write API services to CCI to interact with MDLIVE core, and i have worked and activating pre registered user module.

#### MAR 2014 - JUN 2015

# Software Engineer

ValueLabs LLP

Worked as software Engineer in Value labs for Snapfish project.My responsibility is to write Webservice REST calls to API's in ruby ,Processing the API responses in the front end with Backbone.js frame work and building the product builder.As part of this project i am taking carebackend as well as front end part of application.

#### MAR 2012 - MAR 2014

# Software Engineer

Notous Innovation Inc

- Interacting with business requestor to understand the business requirements.
- Analyzing the functional requirements and tasks estimation.
- Technical design.
- Development for business logic with Ruby on Rails.
- UI development with JavaScript, Html and Css.
- Customizing the existing web services according to functional requirements
- Mongodb programming for backend requirements

# Education

#### 2007 - 2011

# B.Tech (Computer Science & Engineering)

Bhimavaram Institute of Engineering and Technology

### 1995 - 2005

# Secondary School Education

Chaitanya residential school